# SEAN C. LEHMAN (812) 212-2543

# 10069 BENT TREE LANE, FISHERS, IN 46037

E-mail: lehmansean@hotmail.com

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Position focused on software engineering or related field

# **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

Engineering professional with competencies in designing, conceptualizing and managing projects that will increase productivity and overall profit margins. Fifteen years successful experience in project management, integrated systems design, productivity improvement, inside and outside sales, customer service, order processing, plant operations analysis and computer skills involving AutoCAD, Microsoft Word, Excel and Outlook.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### LEHMAN CLOCK REPAIR, Batesville, IN/Fishers, IN 2008 - Present

General Manager/Customer Service: Repair of grandfather, antique mantel, wall and cuckoo clocks, Registered Service Center for Howard Miller and Ridgeway clocks.

- Troubleshooting to determine most effective repair or replacement
- Testing of repair performance to reduce warranty claims and increase quality control, customer satisfaction and company brand
- Generated customer job ticket program to track: Repair progress, document movement details, time studies and customer communication and follow up
- Developed scheduling system for future preventive maintenance and increasing customer base to generate future sales pipeline
- Customer education of their product, its operation and pitfalls
- Clock parts and testing bench design and fabrication for specific products
- Managed invoicing, accounts receivable, installation, relocation and warranty claims

### INTERSYSTEMS, Omaha, NE 2005 - 2008

2006-2008 – Inside Sales Engineer for entire product line:

- Bucket Elevators, Drag Chain Conveyors, Enclosed Belt Conveyors, Samplers, Bulkweighers, and Truck Probes.
- Provided detailed, engineered quotes to contractors.
- Provided process analysis to recommend most cost-effective equipment solution.
- Streamlined quoting procedure to eliminate manual logging, paper printout and filing.

### 2005-2006 - Design Engineer for Bucket Elevator product line:

- Duties included producing AutoCAD shop drawings from customer orders, verifying engineering information (drive shaft sizing, motor and reducer selection, belt and cup selection, explosion vent sizing, belt speed, bearing selection and other specs) using Excel spreadsheet calculation programs.
- Designed special infeed hoppers, leg sections, head, boot and boot cover sections, and service platforms.
- Worked with customers by producing detailed approval drawings and providing technical answers to application questions.
- Worked directly with manufacturing personnel to determine best methods for producing quality components.

### PRATER INDUSTRIES, INC., Bolingbrook, IL 2002 - 2004

Application Sales Engineer for Bulk Material Airlock Division:

- Customer service including quoting, purchasing, ordering and troubleshooting.
- Updated and streamlined quotation procedure.
- Documented quote entry, order entry and return material authorization procedures.
- Revised quote request form.

## KRAUTER STORAGE SYSTEMS, INC., Indianapolis, IN 1997-2002

Project and Design Engineer: Prepared project costs and proposals for capital expenditure requests, provided solutions that had a calculated return on investment and offered increased productivity or better utilization of existing resources, managed projects to completion on time and within budget. Examples of projects:

- ALCOA CSI Designed and managed installation of a turnkey 40' x 40' 2-story in-plant office building including HVAC system, sprinkler system, flooring, lighting and electrical system. \$80,000 project.
- Great Dane Trailers Analyzed customer's method for storage of parts at the assembly line, changed the process to become more organized while increasing efficiency, improving inventory control and restocking time. \$25,000 project
- Thomson Consumer Electronics Conceived a generic order picking system that accommodated 90% of the customer's packages, allowing the layout to be dictated by part number instead of carton size. This increased efficiency and accuracy of picks as well as restocking and inventory control. \$65,000 project

## PROGRESSIVE HANDLING, INC., Elkhart, IN 1994-1997

Sales and Design Engineer: Project management and design of integrated conveyor systems involving specially designed and built equipment, electrical controls and mechanical installations. Examples of projects:

- McCormick & Company Engineered a conveying system for a process that would change in 2 years. Designed the central piece of equipment to accommodate future upgrades with minimal expense and effort. \$150,000 project
- Central Soya Designed an integrated conveyor system to automate finished product packaging. Resulted in re-tasking of personnel and increased efficiency of the operation as well as improving quality control. \$250,000 project
- Nickell Moulding Specially designed racking system utilizing basic raw steel shapes and standard pallet racking to accommodate customer's 16' long pallets. \$25,000 project

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

**Purdue University**, West Lafayette, IN, Bachelor of Science Degree, Computer Integrated Manufacturing, Associates of Applied Science Degree, Mechanical Engineering Technology

Howard Miller Repair Certification